Guide to the Abraham Lincoln miscellany, 1864-2015
Lincoln, Abraham miscellany
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Abraham Lincoln miscellany, 1864-2015
8412
.6 cubic ft.
Newspapers, publications, memorabilia, printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Posters, broadsides, memorabilia, etc., pertaining to Lincoln, particularly to his death and funeral.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Posters, broadsides, memorabilia, etc., pertaining to Lincoln, particularly to his death and funeral. Contents include a Lincoln campaign song, 1864; a Thanksgiving proclamation, State of Wisconsin, April 12, 1865; an item listing the order of the funeral procession at obsequies of President Lincoln, 1865; an item concerning another funeral procession, held at Danville, April 19, 1865; an item on a public meeting in Boone County, Missouri, April 22, 1865; an item concerning a lecture by J.H. Surratt, Dec. 30, 1870, on a plot to kidnap Lincoln; and a poem by Edwin Markham, 1929, titled Lincoln, the man of the people.
"Lincoln and Liberty!!, Tract No. 14, New York, Sept. 18, 1860" political pamphlet issued by the Young Men's Republican Union of the City of New York for Lincoln and Hamlin.
Broadside: "The Irrepressible Conflict or The Republican Barge in Danger," published by Currier & Ives, 1860.
Also, early assassination broadside: "Crutch Extra!!! Important from Washington. Death of President Lincoln. The Assassin Escapes." printed for sick and wounded Union troops at Anapolis and one of the earliest printed descriptions of the assassination. Emancipation Proclamation, General Orders No. 139. Issued from the War Department, Washington, D.C. Signed in print by Abraham Lincoln, President; William H. Seward, Secretary of State; and Lorenzo Thomas, Adjutant General (3pp.). "Golden Sayings of Abraham Lincoln," broadside with 18 quotes from Lincoln. "Little 'Mac'" Copperhead ticket attacking George McClellan's credentials during the 1864 campaign. Harper's Weekly on Lincoln's assassination, May 20, 1865.
Two Abraham Lincoln Centennial souvenir postcards, 1909.
Emancipation Proclamation stamp and first day cover, 2013.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865 -- Death and burial.; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865 -- Assassination.; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865 -- Anniversaries, etc.; Markham, Edwin, 1852-1940.; McClellan, George B. (George Brinton), 1826-1885.; Surratt, John H. (John Harrison), 1844-1916; Currier & Ives.; United States. President (1861-1865: Lincoln).; Young Men's Republican Union of the City of New York.
Titles:
Emancipation Proclamation (United States. President (1861-1865: Lincoln))fast(OCoLC)fst01356258
Subjects:
Anniversaries; Assassination
Form and Genre Terms:
First day covers.; Poetry; Quotations
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Historical documents
Box 1, 3
Series II. Publications
Box 2
Series III. Archival publications and exhibits
Box 2
Series IV. Ephemera
Box 1, 3
Series V. Other miscellaneous items
Box 2, 3
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Historical documents
  - "Lincoln and Hamilton - facts for the people", Tract No. 14, September 18, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lincoln campaign song!, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Obsequies of President Lincoln, order of funeral procession", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Thanksgiving Proclamation, State of Wisconsin, by James T. Lewis, Governor, April 12, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Crutch Extra!!! Important from Washington. Death of President Lincoln. The Assassin Escapes.", 1865 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    -printed for sick and wounded Union troops at Anapolis and one of the earliest printed descriptions of the assassination
  - "Lincoln, The Man of The People", by Edwin Markham, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    -revised version of poem chosen by committee headed by Chief Justice Taft to be read at the dedication of the Lincoln Memorial in 1922
  - Broadside advertising the funeral procession of Lincoln at Danville, April 19, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Death of President Lincoln, public meeting in Boone County, MO.", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Harper's Weekly, May 20, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Political cartoon, "The Irrepressible Conflict, or The Republican Barge in Danger", 1860 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Broadside advertising a lecture by J.H. Surratt at the Odd-Fellow's Hall, December 30, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    -this lecture was cancelled due to opposition
  - "Little 'Mac'" Copperhead ticket, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    -ticket attacking George McClellan's credentials during the 1864 campaign
  - Emancipation Proclamation, General Orders No. 139, September 24, 1862 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    -issued from the War Department, Washington, D.C; signed in print by Abraham Lincoln (President), William H. Seward (Secretary of State) and Lorenzo Thomas (Adjutant General)
- Series II. Publications
  - National Geographic, April 2015 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Newsweek, Lincoln vs. Darwin, July 2008 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - BBC Knowledge, February 2009 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Time Magazine, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Observer, October 17, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "The Campaign for Atlanta!", 1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "The Atlanta Cyclorama of The Battle of Atlanta", 1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Abraham Lincoln, by Amy L. Cohn and Suzy Schmidt, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series III. Archival publications and exhibits
  - Flyer advertising duel Kroch Library exhibits - Emancipation Proclamation and Hip Hop, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Quarto, the Clements Library Associates, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Smithsonian Collector's Edition, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - New York Archives, special issue, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - For the Record, Illinois State Archives newsletter, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Seth Kaller Inc., 2011 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Exhibit programs and flyers, 2008-2013 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper clippings regarding Cornell's exhibits, 2009-2013 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Series IV. Ephemera
  - Bakersfield Condors hockey jersey commemorating 150th anniversary of the Gettysburg Address, 2013; MU-1561 (Box 1)
    -depicts images of Lincoln, a civil war battle, and the Gettysburg Address
  - Pair of socks depicting Lincoln's face, n.d.; MU-1559 (Box 3)
  - Band aids depicting an image of Lincoln, n.d.; MU-1560 (Box 3)
  - Abraham Lincoln note card with sticker quotes, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Series V. Other miscellaneous items
  - Music lyrics, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 200th Birthday Celebration invitations, February 12, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - The Battle of Gettysburg in 3-D, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Gettysburg Address, printed by J. Tyler, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Emancipation Proclamation first day covers, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Birthday commemoration postcards, 1909, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 3)